

Elbert John Orozco

Software Engineer

elbertorozco@protonmail.com

+639274666987

Ortigas Extension, Pasig City, Philippines

bytethenoodle.github.io

linkedin.com/in/elbert-john-orozco-14a110107 in

twitter.com/noodlebytes

github.com/bytethenoodle 👩

instagram.com/elbert_orozco 💿

My overall objective is to learn, build, teach, and improve iOS apps with the latest trends in technology. I have been an iOS software developer since 2014 and is always very passionate in doing it. I am also a hobbyist doing "Internet-of-Things" experiments and other open source projects. I also have a keen interest in data science and to have iOS apps use these technologies for different things.

SKILLS

iOS Swift

wift O

Objective-C

HTML

Cocoa Touch

Foundation

SQL

Core Data

JSON REST

Grand Central Dispatch

iit

Agile

Scrum

Encryption

Networking

Java

Kotlii

CI/CD

WORK EXPERIENCE

iOS Software Engineer

GLOBE FINTECH INNOVATIONS, INC. (Mynt)

09/2020 - Present

Achievements/Tasks

- Develop and/or maintain features for the iOS app
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Assist in diagnosing and fixing of issues

iOS Developer

WINAS Technologies International Philippines Inc.

07/2019 - 04/2020

Mandaluyong City

Taguig City

- 72019 04/2 Tasks
- Develop and/or maintain apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Assist the QA team in planning and performing Unit Tests
- Diagnose and fix issues
- Assist in development of backend apis (PHP Laravel)

Software Engineer Amdocs Philippines

04/2018 - 06/2019

Pasig City

Tasks

- Develop and/or maintain apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Assist the support team and backend in features and diagnosing issues
- Research on features to integrate into app
- Research on latest solutions for mobile software development
- Assist in designing mockups using Adobe XD or Sketch (UI prototyping)
- Develop tools/helpers that will make development easier/faster
- Assist in app feature discussions with business to determine which is plausible or not

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Analyst (iOS)

Smart Communications

12/2016 - 04/2018

Tasks

- Develop and/or maintain apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Assist the support team in features and diagnosing issues
- Research on features to integrate into app
- Research on latest solutions for iOS Development

iOS Developer (Contract)

Asticom Technologies

06/2016 - 11/2016

Z010-11/2010

- Tasks
- Develop internal mobile apps for the iOS platform
- Gather requirements around functionality and design
- Translate requirements into functional app modules
- Assist the support team in features and diagnosing issues
- Research on features to integrate into app
- Research on latest solutions for iOS Development

Mobile Developer

Rogomi Inc

07/2015 - 06/2016 Pasig City

- Tasks
- Gather requirements around functionality and translate those requirements into functional solutions
- Develop mobile applications on assigned platforms
- Assist the Technical Support team in diagnosing bugs and other issues in products
- Assist the QA team with new product releases and bug fixes for products
- Continuously study iOS and/or Android development
- Accomplish miscellaneous I.T.-related tasks

Freelance (Design, Development, Research)

Private Clients

10/2014 - 07/2015 Manila

- Tasks
- Completed embedded system and mobile applications development projects from various clients.
- Pursued personal research on different software platforms such as for the open source Mono .NET project for both desktop
 and mobile applications, the Arduino, and Raspberry Pi for embedded systems and IOT (Internet-of-Things).
- Research on SQL and PHP class wrappers for iOS and Java Android.

On-The-Job Trainee

Philippine Long Distance Telephone

10/2014 - 01/2015 Marikina City

- Tasks
- Assigned to work as a Main Distribution Frame Assistant checking for connection faults to and from the central office.
- Assigned to work as a Local Customer Database Verifier verifying customer accounts to its corresponding port number assignments in the central office in a local database.

Makati City

Taguig City

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

AMA Computer College

01/2014 - 09/2014

Tasks

- Served as one of the developers of an iOS application that displays the information sent wirelessly by an Arduino-Based oscilloscope as part of a school research programme
- Helped the school student development team that completed a revised implementation of an Inventory System Application for employee time sheets written in C# and uses SQL
- Monitored development progress and ran individual testing

Flash Multimedia/Animations Designer Bicol University

09/2009 - 10/2009

Tasks

- Served as one of the developers of flash-based animation presentations for the school's Quiz Bee Competition event

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering

AMA Computer College Manila Campus

05/2015 Manila City

PROJECTS INVOLVED

GCash (2020 - Present)

Runway - jp (2020) 🗷

AeonBank - jp (2019) ☑

OHYA - jp (2019) 🗗

myPLDT Smart (2019) 🗗

PLDT Enterprise 177 app (2018)

Smart360 (2018)

Ka-Partner for Smart Retail (2018)

Smart Infinity (2017 - 2018)

mySmart app (2017 - 2019) 🗷

Talk n' Text app (2017) ♂

"Acqui" app for Globe myBusiness (2016)

BookIt for iPhone (2016) 2

Unilab - PediaLink for iPhone (2015) 🗗

DOT - moreFun for iPhone/iPad (2015)

FunPH for iPhone/iPad (2015)

AgTech Apps for iPhone/iPad (2015)

Embedded System Spec Monitoring App (2015)

Oscilloscope Monitor for iPhone (2014)

Inventory System Application (2014)

Antipolo City

Legazpi City, Albay